edulastic.com 2019-10-28

# privacy | Edulastic

## Privacy Policy

Revised May 30, 2019

**We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of all of our users, including students, to make sure their information is safe, private and available to them. We strive to collect only the data needed to provide and improve services to users. We do not advertise on Edulastic, sell your personal information to anyone, or track users to target ads on other websites.**

We are proud signatories of the Student Privacy Pledge

Edulastic and it’s parent company Snapwiz, Inc. (the “Company,” “Edulastic,” “we,” “us,” “our”), know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared. We take your privacy seriously and are committed to fostering a safe and secure learning environment for all of our users. This Privacy Policy applies to Edulastic websites (edulastic.com, app.edulastic.com, blog.edulastic.com), mobile applications (SnapScore) and other online services (collectively, the “Services”), which are all owned and operated by Snapwiz, Inc. at 39300 Civic Center Drive #310, Fremont, CA 94538. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use and share information which identifies you or is associated with you (“Personal Information”). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your Personal Information and how you can access and update this information. If you are a parent or teacher of a child under thirteen years old, please review the information below pertaining to the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and how we collect, use and disclose the information from and about children under thirteen years old. By visiting any of the Company’s websites or using our Services, you consent to the collection, use and sharing of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

### What information we collect

We collect Personal Information from you when you submit it to us, or use the Services. We may also collect this information from an administrator at your school or district directly or via a third-party integration. We collect Anonymous Information through your use of the Services which is not linked to your Personal Information through cookies and other analytic technologies. See below for more information about how we use cookies. 

#### Information we collect from teachers and administrators

Account information

If you register for an account on the Services, or if your school or district creates an account on your behalf, we may collect your name, email address, a password, your school and/or district, and the classes you teach (grade, subject, class name). If you or your school or district registers through or otherwise grants access to a third-party integrated service (“Integrated Service”), such as Google, MS365 or Clever, we may collect Personal Information that is already associated with your Integrated Service account. If you create or upload assessments or other academic or educational resources or materials (“Educational Materials”), we collect the content of these materials and metadata you provide about them, such as tags, DOK levels and alignment to learning standards. 

Payment information

If you make a purchase through our Services, we will collect information needed to complete the transaction, including but not limited to your e-mail address, credit card information, and name on your credit card. We do not process, record or maintain your credit card or bank account information. 

Communications information

If you contact us via online submission, telephone, electronic mail or regular mail, we may keep a record of that correspondence. If you post comments or opinions to us on the Services or third-party websites where we have a profile or presence (e.g. on our Facebook page), we may keep a record of the comments. 

Information about how you use the Service

We collect data about how you use the Services such the time you access the Service and duration you are on it, the website you come to the Service from, selections and choices you make and preferences that you set when using the Service as well as any data you input while conducting any assessment on the Service. 

Information about how you connect to the Service

We collect data about the computer or other electronic device (“device”) you use to connect to the Service such as details about the type of device (which can include unique device identifying numbers), its operating system, browser and applications connected to the Service through the device, your Internet service provider or mobile network, your IP address and your devices telephone number (if it has one). While we collect the location of your school or district, we do not automatically collect information about your actual location, other than an approximate location (usually no more precise than city level), which can be determined from your IP address. 

#### Information we collect from students

Account information

No personally identifiable information, such as name or email address is required to create a student account on the Services. However, if a student, teacher or school or district administrator provides it, we may collect the student’s name, a username (which may be an email address or student ID number), a password, the student’s school and/or district, and their class enrollments (grade, subject, class name, teacher). 

Demographic information

If a student’s teacher or school or district administrator provides it, we may collect a student’s demographic information such as age, gender, race and eligibility for school services solely for the purpose of providing the Services. We do not share or use this information for any other purpose. 

Assessment information

As a student uses the Services, we collect information such as time and duration of accessing the Services, assessment responses and scores, number of attempts and teacher feedback. 

### How we use your information

#### Information from and about Teachers and Administrators

We use the information we collect from teachers and administrators in the following ways: 

To provide the Services to you and your school or district

We use information collected from teachers, administrators and students to create and manage accounts, administer assessments and produce reports of usage patterns and assessment results. Users can access this data based on their role, for example, students may access data only about their account. Teachers may access data about their own account, or those of students currently or previously enrolled in their classes. Administrators may access data about teachers and students in their school or district, respectively. 

To personalize the Services

We use information collected from teachers and administrators to display information and features that may be of interest to you, or tailored to how you use the Services. For example, we display assessment content relevant to your subject area and optimize the display for the device you’re using. We may display names of teachers who have created accounts on the Services to teachers who join the same school or district. 

To improve the Services

We use information collected from teachers and administrators to understand and analyze usage trends and preferences of our users to improve the functionality of the Services. We also use this data to diagnose and address technical issues with the Services, detect and investigate illegal activities, breaches of any agreements entered into between you and us and threats to the security of the Services. 

To provide you with information about our products or services

We use information collected from teachers and administrators to respond to your inquiries and address comments and issues you have in relation to your use of the Service. We also use this information to notify you of changes to the Service, or provide you information about products or services that we feel may interest you, in accordance with your marketing preferences. We do not share Personal Information of any of our users with third parties for their marketing purposes, nor track users to target advertisements on Edulastic or other websites. 

#### Information from and about Students

We use the information we collect from and about students only to provide the Services to teachers, schools and districts. We use information collected from teachers, administrators and students to create and manage accounts, administer assessments and produce reports of assessment results. Student data may only be accessed by the student, a parent or guardian, the student’s teachers or an administrator at the student’s school or district. We use aggregated and de-identified student information, such as assessment responses and scores, to analyze and improve the quality of questions in our item banks. We do not allow advertising on any part of the Services, do not sell any student information, and do not track students to target ads on other websites. 

### When we share your information

We do not sell your personal information. We will disclose the Personal Data that we collect from you only as described in this Privacy Policy. 

#### We share information you explicitly authorize us to share

Any assessments or assessment questions you create or upload to a shared library will be accessible to other users with access to that library. If you share a draft assessment with other users in order to collaborate with them, those users will have access to your assessment. If you or a school or district administrator on your behalf adds a co-teacher to your class, the co-teacher will have access to teacher and student data in your account. Students do not have the ability to share any data about themselves publicly. 

#### We share information with administrative users at schools and districts

Administrators with access to the school or district version of Edulastic can view and edit teacher and student data in their school or district, including profile data, usage data, assessment responses and results, and individual and aggregated reports. 

#### We may share information with third parties that provide a service to us or to you

To provide the Services to you, we use other companies for services like hosting, messaging, tracking support issues and analytics. We only contract with third party vendors whose privacy policies are consistent with this policy. These third parties are required not to use your Personal Data other than to provide these services to us and your school or district. We may share aggregated and de-identified data, such as student responses and scores, with publishers of third-party item banks that you have purchased for the purpose of improving the quality of their assessment questions. If you request that we share data with a third-party partner, such as a curriculum publisher, to provide services to you or your school or district, we will ask you to explicitly provide permission for the data to be shared. We will not disclose Personal Data to third parties for marketing or any purposes not described in this Privacy Policy. 

#### We may disclose information in a change of business

In the event that we sell or buy or transfer any business or assets (in part or whole), we may disclose your personal information to the prospective buyer or recipient of such business or assets. We will notify you via email and prominently on our website prior to such a transfer and provide you information on your choices to limit or prohibit transfer of your Personal Information. 

#### We will share data when required by law, or to protect us and others

We may disclose user information to respond to a subpoena, court order or other legal duty or obligation (including without limitations requests or demands from law enforcement and government authorities and regulators). We may also disclose information to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual prohibited activities, including but not limited to, fraud and situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or to prevent financial loss to any person or entity. 

### Use of cookies and other technologies

Cookies are small pieces of text sent by your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows the Services or a third party to recognize you and make your next visit easier and the Service more useful to you. Cookies can be "persistent" or "session" cookies. When you use and access the Service, we may place cookies files in your web browser. We use cookies for the following purposes: to enable certain functions of the Services, to store your preferences, to report usage statistics of the Services and to ensure functionality of the Service such as load balancing and fraud prevention. We do not use cookies to serve third-party advertisements, nor to target users with behavioral advertising. If you'd like to delete cookies or instruct your web browser to delete or refuse cookies, please visit the help pages of your web browser. Please note, however, that if you delete cookies or refuse to accept them, you might not be able to use all of the features we offer, you may not be able to store your preferences, and some of our pages might not display properly. 

### Child Users

#### Child Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance (“COPPA”)

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important to us, so we have added protections and restrictions designed to help protect Personal Information relating to children who are less than 13 years of age (“Child Users”). We only collect Personal Information through the Services from a child under 13 where a teacher or administrator from that student’s school or district has agreed to obtain parental consent for that child to use the Services and to disclose Personal Information to us, for the use and benefit of the learning environment. If you are a student under 13, please do not send any Personal Information about yourself to us if your school, district, and/or teacher has not obtained this prior consent from your parent or guardian, and please do not send any personal information other than what we request from you in connection with the Services. If we learn we have collected personal information from a student under 13 without parental consent being obtained by his or her school, district, and/or teacher, or if we learn a student under 13 has provided us Personal Information beyond what we request from him or her, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a student under 13 may have provided us Personal Information in violation of this paragraph, please contact us at [support@edulastic.com](mailto:support@edulastic.com) If you are a school, district, or teacher, you represent and warrant that you are solely responsible for complying with COPPA, meaning that you must obtain advance written consent from all parents or guardians whose children under 13 will be accessing the Services. You are responsible for understanding how any Publisher Software (defined and described below) that you install on behalf of yourself or other users may collect and use information of users of Edulastic’s Services. When obtaining consent, you must provide parents and guardians with this Privacy Policy. You can find you can find a [sample parent permission slip here](https://edulastic.com/docs/edulastic-sample-permission-slip.pdf). You must keep all consents on file and provide them to us if we request them. If you are a teacher, you represent and warrant that you have permission and authorization from your school and/or district to use the Services as part of your curriculum, and for purposes of COPPA compliance, you represent and warrant that you are entering into these Terms on behalf of your school and/or district. As a Parent, you have the ability to control information about your Child User. To review, update, or delete information collected from your Child User contact us at [support@edulastic.com](mailto:support@edulastic.com). 

#### California Children’s Privacy Rights

If you are under the age of 18, or the parent of a User under the age of 18, residing in California, you are entitled to request removal of content or information you have posted on our Services. If you would like to request removal of your or your child’s content or information, please email us at [support@edulastic.com](mailto:support@edulastic.com) for assistance. Please note that removal of your content or information does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal, as there may be deidentified or recoverable elements of your content or information on our servers in some form. Additionally, we will not remove content or information that we may be required to retain under applicable federal and state laws. 

### How we keep your data secure

We have implemented a variety of security measures to protect the personal information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. We encrypt Personal Data while at rest, and protect your login information and the transmission of data using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your account by creating and maintaining a strong password and keeping it private. While Edulastic employees may ask for your username to provide you support, we will not ask for your password. If we learn of a data security incident that compromises or appears to compromise your Personal Information, then we will attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We may also post a notice on the Services if a data security incident occurs. We delete data when it is no longer necessary to provide services to you and your school or district, or when requested by a school or district at the termination of a contract. 

### Links to other sites

The Services may link to and may be linked by websites operated by other entities or individuals. Some of these websites, such as our Facebook page and YouTube channel, may be co-branded with our name or logo. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot always control the activities of, such other third-party websites. You should consult the respective privacy policies of those third-party websites. 

### International visitors

Our Properties are operated and managed on servers located within the United States. If you choose to use our Properties from the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that differ from U.S. law, then you acknowledge and agree that you are transferring your Personal Information outside of those regions to the United States and that, by providing your Personal Information on the Properties, you consent to that transfer. 

### Your choices regarding your personal data

You have several choices regarding our use of your information on our Services: 

#### Accessing and deleting your personal information

  * You may opt not to provide, or later edit or delete any of the non-required information from your Personal Data through the profile page in your account on our Sites or Apps.
  * You may request deletion of your Personal Data or your entire account by contacting us at [support@edulastic.com](mailto:support@edulastic.com). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request.
  * Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified or deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Sites or Apps for a period of time.

#### Marketing сommunications

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to teachers and administrators about our services, products, or events. You may opt out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the email. If you opt out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you administrative e-mails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us. 

#### Disconnecting from an Integrated Services

You may revoke Edulastic’s access to your account on any Integrated Service, such as Google, at any time by updating the appropriate settings in the account preferences of the respective Integrated Service. You should check your privacy settings on each Integrated Service to understand and change the information sent to us through each Integrated Service. Please review each Integrated Service’s terms of use and privacy policies carefully before using their services and connecting to our Services. 

#### Disabling сookies

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Sites who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Sites, but some features may not be available to you. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

This Privacy Policy is current as of the Last Updated Date set forth above. We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in our information processing practices. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you at the email address that we have on file for you in advance of the change becoming effective. If you disagree with such announced changes to this policy, you will have an opportunity to cancel your account and delete your data before the policy goes into effect. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. 

### How to contact us

Please contact us with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, your personal information, our third-party disclosure practices, or your consent choices by: 

**Email:** [support@edulastic.com](mailto:support@edulastic.com)

**Phone:** 510-901-4739

**Fax:** 510-257-5436

**Mail:** Edulastic, 39300 Civic Center Drive #310, Fremont, CA 94538
